<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsoons</title>
    <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Monsoons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theotherkhan.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ablutions</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ablutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ablutions/</guid>
      <description>nostalgic piety and I break with fruit ablution clarity, repeatedly and increasingly and defeatedly water is drawn over post truth calluses, slathered: Over this body in beauty – that’s all that matters, the sublime – dancing – yes I’m not practicing – any day now my son you will return. I (hypocrite) stand gleaming by the kitchen sink, turning to look at her unrotten hope, fearing its expiration when she hands me fruit</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the L train isn&#39;t running</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/train/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/train/</guid>
      <description>Excerpts from the L train isnt running :
the L train / isn&amp;rsquo;t running / i guess / i&amp;rsquo;ll tread / the long route / this time / sometimes / it can be nice / to forget / all the laws / counting pebbles / on a chain / smoking / cigarette / fumes / my lungs / refreshed / on the sunlit steps / of a giant / a glass house / of canvases / coated / in hues / of New York / of Hopper / sweet Whitney / dirty Whitney / crowds / leak / in / out / a tiny crevice / to know waiting / is to know living / to read a book / or sing / a song / a stare / far enough / at the seam / the river / slips / into the sky //</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinetoscope (ft. men)</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/kinetoscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/kinetoscope/</guid>
      <description>Late to play, I rush to him Allahu la ilaha – the rhythmic murmur begins he blows hurriedly on his restive child Climbing trees, eating muddy leaves – I frisk, I fall Back at home, solace lingers unbound
A wrinkled, disquiet hand my grip gently placating his A hospital bed basking in sunlight Dada’s intent gaze – reading mine Asked me not to stay, said no goodbyes
In the garage of my ancestral home, laid a loved one’s coffin A moment of unassailable grief slightly eased Untouched by words – my palm, gently squeezed</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surbahar</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/surbahar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/surbahar/</guid>
      <description>Surbahar plays heart out to nothing Stepping out past step or notion Life is best lived remotely – that childhood Observing only, sentiment sealing (sophisticated security) Listen it&amp;rsquo;s quite blue after a hundred notes and silent after a thousand? It&amp;rsquo;s the blankness of your eyes aajkal Akin to modern masters, their vacant canvas or patternless jazz Shows over, airtight silence hums under, dark sky over The way wind interrogates through unsemantic beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/lucky/</guid>
      <description>Jostling against tiny shoulders You make your way through A moment’s pause at the threshold – No time to spare A hurried entrance A foregone goodbye What is this place? First glance – Eyes met with grandeur An apparent immaculacy Ceilings high Walls paneled A grand chandelier Over a marble floor A helical staircase Carved handrails Going up Going down Take your pick There’s some noise downstairs A jamboree of sorts You walk towards it And look up The light falling through the skylight Equally enticing Time is running fast How do you choose?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bones</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/bones/</guid>
      <description>Cook with the meat on the bone I rip through myself looking for bones Authenticity, I only seek things I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in, God Here are the maps my uncles prepared
The scrolls soak in tea until the borders disappear into milk I tell other people who they are not so that I can name myself
It&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted — a new name Same skin, new bones, white milk, home My uncle asks if I pray for here or home I stay silent, suspended in disbelief</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes: On community building</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/notes/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/notes/community/</guid>
      <description>Reading is, for most of us, a solitary activity. On the subway, over lunch breaks, during layovers, curled up in bed - no matter where we are, books allows us to escape, if only momentarily, into our own world. While reading circles can provide forums for discussion, and for sharing the worlds we build during reading with others, in my experience they can feel stuffy, require assigned reading, and become transient as people come and go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tollund Man</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/tollund/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/tollund/</guid>
      <description>two thousand years ago with my bare eye i encountered a Mars of spore &amp;amp; dry grass. but
here mildew permeates my routine. i spray the killer, spray &amp;amp; shine &amp;amp; behold! a circumstantial vacuum
concedes my sins &amp;amp; perfect absence feels so near. now look below: i, the tollund
man, am buried here and my grimace forewarns of a particular home-video-grief. now am I
speaking to a grandfather or some artificial intelligence?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>گر پڑے نیچے سارے ستارے</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ghazal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ghazal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes: Interconnections</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/notes/diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/notes/diagram/</guid>
      <description>The world of Urdu shairi is deeply interconnected - and in constant conversation with the wider world. This diagram depicts relationships between poets we covered during shairi in 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestor</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ancestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ancestor/</guid>
      <description>Confusing myself for the bad deed
I woke up at sunrise and said: not anymore Like escaping your own smell And I would molt skin and bone but my ancestor said: the scent lingers
Incarcerated firefighters today announced a breakthrough I was heartbroken in believing the progress
Retaliations confused us, we thought we had quenched it safely in the near east (the far west) until the jungles melted to a virus of trash bags masked in tropical fragrance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/unititled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/unititled/</guid>
      <description>Two brothers walked in the alleyway the way I wish I could with you
My uncle asked: do you pray for America or Pakistan? I said both, ashamed of my disbelief
Here faith is rain and I seek truth in the nuqta In our chowk the smog chokes like time did when I put garlands in her hair or the moment before a drone converts a village to an archaeology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildfire</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/wildfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/wildfire/</guid>
      <description>I was a believer and it&amp;rsquo;s wildfire season
Prove yourself to your homelands but dont move back My corporation goes to trial and settles: intermittent recycling programs My algorithm suggests buying crescent moon jewelry Dear all: but all too late. Flooding fires, fiery floods, the flight I unoriginate away in the ozone tearing privilege of heritage jetting
Responsibility shoved into words: this poem The confusion of profit, of prophets Iconoclasm: surgical strike of the starbucks straws Common bloodletting amongst the dunes (Allahuakbar)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Monsoons</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! This is a blog for poetry, shairi notes, and other musings. Updated monthly.
Current contributors: Hasan Khan Zainab Akhtar Ishaan Saxena mosambiyaar</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Subscribe for our monthly newsletter!
Enter your email address
powered by TinyLetter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 dead at Arcade America</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/prose/aa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/prose/aa/</guid>
      <description>For three minutes, twenty-one players at Arcade America watched Sameer convulse on the floor.
Witnesses recall Sameer Shaheed, a 12-year-old refugee boy, calling out before the time of his death. Sameer had been playing Stormhill, a popular virtual reality game set in a fictionalized version of his home country.
“I remember being scared at the time. His words sounded like the bad guys from Stormhill,” said Lyola Thomas, a frequent customer at Arcade America.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
