<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsoons</title>
    <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Monsoons</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Lucky</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/lucky/</guid>
      <description>Jostling against tiny shoulders You make your way through A moment’s pause at the threshold – No time to spare A hurried entrance A foregone goodbye What is this place? First glance – Eyes met with grandeur An apparent immaculacy Ceilings high Walls paneled A grand chandelier Over a marble floor A helical staircase Carved handrails Going up Going down Take your pick There’s some noise downstairs A jamboree of sorts You walk towards it And look up The light falling through the skylight Equally enticing Time is running fast How do you choose?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bones</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/bones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/bones/</guid>
      <description>Cook with the meat on the bone I rip through myself looking for bones Authenticity, I only seek things I dont believe in, God Here are the maps my uncles prepared
The scrolls soak in tea until the borders disappear into milk I tell other people who they are not so that I can name myself
It&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted, a new name Same skin, new bones, white milk, home My uncle asks if I pray for here or home I stay silent, suspended in disbelief</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tollund Man</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/tollund/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/tollund/</guid>
      <description>two thousand years ago with my bare eye i encountered a Mars of spore &amp;amp; dry grass. but
here mildew permeates my routine. i spray the killer, spray &amp;amp; shine &amp;amp; behold! a circumstantial vacuum
concedes my sins &amp;amp; perfect absence feels so near. now look below: i, the tollund
man, am buried here and my grimace forewarns of a particular home-video-grief. now am I
speaking to a grandfather or some artificial intelligence?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ghazal</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ghazal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ghazal/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ancestor</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ancestor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/ancestor/</guid>
      <description>Confusing myself for the bad deed
I woke up at sunrise and said: not anymore Like escaping your own smell And I would molt skin and bone but my ancestor said: the scent lingers
Incarcerated firefighters today announced a breakthrough I was heartbroken in believing the progress
Retaliations confused us, we thought we had quenched it safely in the near east (the far west) until the jungles melted to a virus of trash bags masked in tropical fragrance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/unititled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/unititled/</guid>
      <description>Two brothers walked in the alleyway the way I wish I could with you
My uncle asked: do you pray for America or Pakistan? I said both, ashamed of my disbelief
Here faith is rain and I seek truth in the nuqta In our chowk the smog chokes like time did when I put garlands in her hair or the moment before a drone converts a village to an archaeology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildfire</title>
      <link>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/wildfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theotherkhan.github.io/poetry/wildfire/</guid>
      <description>I was a believer and it&amp;rsquo;s wildfire season
Prove yourself to your homelands but dont move back My corporation goes to trial and settles: intermittent recycling programs My algorithm suggests buying crescent moon jewelry Dear all: but all too late. Flooding fires, fiery floods, the flight I unoriginate away in the ozone tearing privilege of heritage jetting
Responsibility shoved into words: this poem The confusion of profit, of prophets Iconoclasm: surgical strike of the starbucks straws Common bloodletting amongst the dunes (Allahuakbar)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
