<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Rumuuz</title>
    <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Rumuuz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://monsoons-blog.github.io/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Urdu Magazines</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/magazines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/magazines/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Genesis of Urdu</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/origins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/origins/</guid>
      <description>Legend has it that Urdu began with the Mughal invasions of the Indian Subcontinent. Bred in diverse war camps – the word is derived from the Turkish ‘ordu’ meaning army – Urdu has often been portrayed as a khichri of Turkish, Farsi, Arabic and Hindi originally used for military communications. Growing up, a friend of mine liked to recount that Urdu began with the poetic genius of Amir Khusrao, who wove verses from Farsi and local dialects into language forming ghazals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes: Interconnections</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/diagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/diagram/</guid>
      <description>The world of Urdu shayari is deeply interconnected - and in constant conversation with the wider world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes:   خُوش نَوِیسی</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/calligraphy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/calligraphy/</guid>
      <description>We often draw whiteboard calligraphy (خُوش نَوِیسی) to accompany our sessions. A few recent ones:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Garden 🥀</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/garden/</guid>
      <description>The Garden is a recurring theme in Urdu shairi. From serving as a metaphor of paradise to acting as a container for other motifs (the rose, the nightingale, the moth), gardens hold varying symbolisms in adab. This week we’ll explore the garden through a writing workshop. First we’ll read a collection of ashaar where the garden and its elements play differing symbolic roles, followed by working on our own poetry using the imagery discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Guide</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/guide/</guid>
      <description>Ghazals 🔗Overview
Originating in 7th century Arabia, this form of shairi has historically focused on matters of love (spiritual or worldy), with a particular emphasis on separation and reunification with the beloved. While the technical constraints are strict, ghazals do not need to have a single topic running through the poem. Rather, they emphasize a tone or a mood more than any narrative continuity. Often abstract, ghazals employ contradictions, opposites and multiplicities of meaning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes: On community building</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/community/</guid>
      <description>Reading is, for most of us, a solitary activity. On the subway, over lunch breaks, during layovers, curled up in bed - no matter where we are, books allows us to escape, if only momentarily, into our own world. While reading circles can provide forums for discussion, and for sharing the worlds we build during reading with others, in my experience they can feel stuffy, require assigned reading, and become transient as people come and go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shairi notes: Jeopardy</title>
      <link>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/jeopardy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://monsoons-blog.github.io/notes/jeopardy/</guid>
      <description>Jeaopardy is an annual Shairi tradition. The following board represents a year-in-review of all the poems we&amp;rsquo;ve covered over the past year:
Online Jeopardy Maker - JeopardyLabs! </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
